(832) 820-4687 tasharbivins@gmail.com

PATIENT CARE ASSISTANT

Possess the vision and expertise necessary to drive optimum patient care, clinical processes, sterile procedures and quality improvements to enhance patient outcomes

Multifaceted and patient-focused Certified Nurse Assistant and Phlebotomist offering strong qualifications in direct patient care, accurate charting, vital signs, assignment prioritization, assessments and patient education for industry leading healthcare organizations. Adept at contributing to the continuity of patient care through admission/discharge procedures, ADL's, basic life support, ambulating, blood draws, IV fluids, intake/output, abnormal findings and safety objectives. Commended for outstanding clinical/laboratory skills, teamwork, compassion and commitment to the nursing profession.

ADDED-VALUE OFFERED

Patient Safety | Interdisciplinary Collaboration | Dynamic Leadership | Laboratory Testing & Analysis
Routine Rounds | Infection Control | Patient/Family Advocate | Vital Signs | Point of Care Testing
Blood Bank | EKG Leads | Body Measurements | Physiologic Monitoring | EPIC Documentation | Quality Improvements
Intake & Output | Data Integrity | Patient Privacy & Dignity | Medical Equipment | Hygienic Care | Order Entry

Technological Proficiency: MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint), EPIC, Westlaw & LexisNexis.

Professional Work History

UT SOUTHWESTERN MEDICAL CENTER - Dallas, TX

05/21/2018 - Present

Health Unit Coordinator - Zale Lipshy Hospital (Pre-Surgery Assessment Clinic)

Standard administrative duties and responsibilities.

- Answer in-coming telephone calls, send and receive facsimile.
- Schedule, re-schedule, and cancel pre-surgery testing appointments on EPIC for surgery patients.
- Maintain patient's pre-op charts.
- Order and maintain unit supplies through Peoplesoft.

TEXAS CHILDRENS HOSPITAL - Houston, TX

09/10/2012 - 03/21/2018

Patient Care Assistant - Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU)

Coordinate and execute all aspects of direct infant care, assessments, vital sign recording, laboratory processes and medical/flow charting for Level II, III and IV NICU units within a major pediatric hospital.

- Instrumental in performing admission/discharge activities, newborn screens, sterilization techniques, heel stick blood draws for bilirubin, CBCs, glucoses and electrolytes, EKG monitoring and FOC measurements for multiple births, pre-mature and critical care infants.
- Provide exceptional training and education to new parents on car seat installs, bottle feedings, bathing, proper use of crib/sleep techniques, swaddling and hand washing.
- Quickly respond to code situations including neonate cardiac and extubation procedures.
- Interface with neonatologists, RN's, cardiologist, gastroenterologist, internal medicine and plastic surgeons to assist with specialized testing/procedures including tracheostomy tubes, ECMO, gastroschisis conditions, Omphalocele Hernia and congenital cardiac malformations.
- Contributed to reducing the number of milk errors by implementing the Milk Safety Errors Verification Process.
- Earned over 50 STARS for dedication to patient care, clinical performance, laboratory skills and optimizing patient care delivery systems.
- Participated on the Retention Committee to promote and organize company events and birthday recognitions.

TASHA BIVINS Page 2

ST. JOSEPH HOSPITAL - Houston, TX

06/06/2011 - 08/31/2012

Patient Care Assistant II - General Surgery

Facilitated and led pre/post-operative patient care, specimen collections and EKG/telemetry monitoring for a high-volume general acute care hospital.

- Deliver notable patient education and home care instructions upon discharge.
- Played an integral role in reporting abnormalities regarding patient's health, inserting foley, colostomies and urinary catheters, assessing IV site/PICC line, providing ambulatory assistance/care for patients recovering from bile duct, appendix, gall bladder, small bowel obstruction, hemorrhoid, stomach, and esophagus surgeries.
- Followed aseptic procedures and provided care in accordance with universal precautions with an emphasis on surgical/traumatic wound care, activities of daily living (ADL) and intake and output.

THE METHODIST HOSPITAL - Houston, TX

End 01/31/2011

Patient Care Assistant II - Emergency Room

Maintained accountability for preparing wounds, clinical workflow, conducting patient rounds and assisting physicians with various medical procedures including lumbar puncture, childbirth, manual fecal impaction, shoulder reduction and suturing various body parts for a leading hospital in Houston.

- Established reputation for effectively training personnel in all areas of laboratory procedures, quality control and equipment functionality.
- Demonstrated a keen ability to identify and correct discrepancies, record and communicate test results and perform glucose testing, 12-lead ECG placement, IV starts and urine, blood & body fluid specimen collection.
- Consistently monitored and observed patients with psychiatric, suicidal, homicidal and behavioral conditions.
- Applied splints to forearm, elbow, wrist, fingers, hand and toes.

THE METHODIST HOSPITAL - Houston, TX

Start 04/23/2007

Patient Care Assistant - Oncology

Full scope of responsibility included intake/output documentation, patient transportation/ambulation and specimen collection for acutely ill adults and geriatric oncology patients with cardiac, medical, surgical and post-critical care needs.

- Sustained partnerships with RN, Charge RN, patients and caregivers to provide support services, compassionate
 care and assist with clinical tasks.
- Entrusted with providing quality care for up to 15 patients per shift while maintaining efficient control of hourly rounds, lab draws, vital signs, data reporting, self-care needs, patient safety, infection control and treatments.

Recognition & Awards

- Received multiple Letters of Recognition and acknowledgement throughout tenure from OB/GYN's, MD's, RN's managers, directors, co-workers, and patients.
- Notable accolades from attending physicians at Parkland Memorial Hospital and Methodist Medical Center for superior labor/delivery patient care and during surgical/gynecological procedures including Cesarean Sections, Dilation & Curettage, Hysterectomies, Tubal Ligations, Cerclages and postpartum care.

Professional Development

PARALEGAL INTERN - Harris County District Attorney's Office, Houston, TX

- Acquired a variety of experience and skills in the areas of legal administration, trial preparation, research, docket management and litigation processes for the Family Criminal Law Division.
- Worked closely with prosecutors and attorneys to develop transcriptions of recordings, subpoenas, motions, notices and trial exhibits for clients who committed felonies and misdemeanors.
- Managed multiple priorities, caseload and deadlines, appropriately handled confidential information, edited/proofread legal documents, drafted pleadings, correspondences & discovery and communicated professionally with all levels of the organization including Division Chief, defendants, witnesses and plaintiffs.

TASHA BIVINS Page 3

Early Career History

PATIENT CARE ASSISTANT, NEURO REHAB SPECIALIST – Centre for Neuro Skills, Irving, TX

PATIENT CARE ASSISTANT – Augustine Personal Home Care Services, Dallas, TX

OB SURGICAL TECH, PATIENT CARE TECHNICIAN – Charlton Methodist Hospital, L&D/Postpartum, Dallas, TX

OB SURGICAL TECH, PATIENT CARE ASSISTANT – Parkland Memorial Hospital, L&D/NICU, Dallas, TX

OB ASSISTANT, PCA II & PHLEBOTOMIST – Stella Jones, MD. Obstetrics & Gynecology Clinic, New Orleans, LA

PATIENT CARE ASSISTANT – St. Paul Hospital, Medical Surgical & Telemetry, Dallas, TX

Education & Credentials

HOUSTON COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Certificate in Paralegal Studies 112 hours, May 28, 2015

Coursework in Legal Research, Texas Civil Litigation & Legal Writing

MANSFIELD BUSINESS SCHOOL - Nursing Assistant & Phlebotomist Training, May 16, 1990

Certified & Registered Nursing Assistant (CNA) – License #NA 109978, Renew 11/9/2019

Basic Life Support (BLS), Advanced Cardio Life Support (ACLS), Automatic External Defibrillator (AED) Renew 9/24/2019

Accelerated EKG Interpretation Course – RHD Memorial Medical Center, October 4, 2004

Basic Dysrhythmia Course – Methodist Dallas Medical Center, November 3, 2004